<root>
   <name>LDAP Re-auth on Approval</name>
   <key>ldapreauth</key>
   <state>stable</state>
   <logo>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/embxrdev/glpi-ldapreauth/main/ldapreauth.png</logo>
   <description>
      <short>
         <en>Require an LDAP/Windows re-authentication before a ticket approval is accepted or rejected.</en>
         <de>Erfordert eine LDAP-/Windows-Neuanmeldung, bevor eine Ticket-Genehmigung akzeptiert oder abgelehnt wird.</de>
      </short>
      <long>
         <en>Adds a Windows/LDAP credential prompt to the ticket and change approval (TicketValidation / ChangeValidation) flows. When an approver answers a validation (accepts or rejects), the plugin verifies the supplied credentials with a direct LDAP bind before the decision is written and requires that the LDAP user matches the signed-in GLPI approver. A four-eyes principle is always enforced: the requester of a validation can never answer it themselves. Successful and blocked decisions are recorded in the ticket or change history. Useful for regulated or traceable approval workflows that need an explicit re-authentication step rather than relying on the existing session. Works with Active Directory (direct bind via UPN/NetBIOS) as well as generic LDAP directories such as OpenLDAP (composed-DN bind or search &amp; bind below a base DN), over ldaps://, StartTLS or plain ldap://. A guided, step-by-step configuration form under Setup &gt; General covers all environment specifics.</en>
         <de>Fügt den Genehmigungsprozessen für Tickets und Changes (TicketValidation / ChangeValidation) eine Windows-/LDAP-Anmeldeabfrage hinzu. Beantwortet ein Genehmiger eine Validierung (Akzeptieren oder Ablehnen), prüft das Plugin die Anmeldedaten per direktem LDAP-Bind, bevor die Entscheidung gespeichert wird, und verlangt, dass der LDAP-Benutzer mit dem angemeldeten GLPI-Benutzer übereinstimmt. Ein Vier-Augen-Prinzip wird immer durchgesetzt: Der Anforderer einer Validierung kann sie nie selbst beantworten. Erfolgreiche und blockierte Entscheidungen werden in der Historie des Tickets bzw. Changes protokolliert. Funktioniert mit Active Directory (Direkt-Bind über UPN/NetBIOS) sowie generischen LDAP-Verzeichnissen wie OpenLDAP (zusammengesetzter DN oder Suchen &amp; Binden unterhalb eines Basis-DN), über ldaps://, StartTLS oder ldap://. Ein geführtes Schritt-für-Schritt-Konfigurationsformular unter Setup &gt; Allgemein deckt alle Umgebungseinstellungen ab.</de>
      </long>
   </description>
   <homepage>https://embxr.eu</homepage>
   <download>https://github.com/embxrdev/glpi-ldapreauth/releases</download>
   <issues>https://github.com/embxrdev/glpi-ldapreauth/issues</issues>
   <readme>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/embxrdev/glpi-ldapreauth/main/README.md</readme>
   <authors>
      <author>Robin Embacher (embxr)</author>
   </authors>
   <versions>
      <version>
         <num>1.2.0</num>
         <compatibility>~11.0.0</compatibility>
         <download_url>https://github.com/embxrdev/glpi-ldapreauth/releases/download/v1.2.0/ldapreauth-1.2.0.tar.bz2</download_url>
      </version>
   </versions>
   <langs>
      <lang>en_GB</lang>
      <lang>cs_CZ</lang>
      <lang>de_DE</lang>
      <lang>es_ES</lang>
      <lang>fr_FR</lang>
      <lang>it_IT</lang>
      <lang>ja_JP</lang>
      <lang>nl_NL</lang>
      <lang>pl_PL</lang>
      <lang>pt_BR</lang>
      <lang>ru_RU</lang>
      <lang>tr_TR</lang>
      <lang>zh_CN</lang>
   </langs>
   <license>GPL v2+</license>
   <tags>
      <en>
         <tag>ldap</tag>
         <tag>authentication</tag>
         <tag>approval</tag>
         <tag>validation</tag>
         <tag>security</tag>
      </en>
   </tags>
   <screenshots>
      <screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/embxrdev/glpi-ldapreauth/main/docs/screenshot-config.png</screenshot>
      <screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/embxrdev/glpi-ldapreauth/main/docs/screenshot-approval.png</screenshot>
   </screenshots>
</root>
